Finding Aid for the Andrew and Mattie Haun Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Andrew and Mattie Haun Papers
November 2007
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0197
.84 linear feet
Biographical Note
This collection holds papers of Andrew Jacob Haun and his wife Mattie Francis Oliver Haun. Following is a chronology:
1870 Andrew Haun born in Hamblen County, Tennessee
1887 Andrew Haun enters Tusculum College in Greeneville, Tennessee
1888 Andrew Haun received L.I. degree from Tusculum College
1893 Andrew Haun moves to Nashville, Tennessee to teach elementary school
1898 Mattie Oliver and Andrew Haun married on July 7
1910 Moved to Franklin, Tennessee where Andrew Haun was principal of the elementary school and superintendent of the city schools.
1945 Andrew Haun retires; Mattie Haun dies on November 19th.
1947 Andrew Haun dies.
Scope and Content Note
This small collection of two Hollinger boxes (.84 linear feet) contains correspondence and personal and biographical materials relating to Andrew Jacob Haun and Mattie Francis Oliver Haun, aunt and uncle of the southern writer Mildred E. Haun, whose papers are also held by Special Collections in the Vanderbilt University Library
- File Listing
  - Correspondence
    - Incoming – 4 telegrams to Mrs. A.J. Haun, May 20, 1918; April 22, 1919; April 24, 1919; April 26, 1919; 1 cablegram, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Incoming - from Phifer, Kenneth G., Dec.7, 1944; Rehorn, Edward, July 22, 1911; Scales, John D., July 29, 1911; Stoddard, Cora Frances, Nov. 25, 1924; Whiteman, W.I., Feb. 23, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Incoming – from Lizzie ( no surname dated March 29, 1887); letter with illegible signature dated, April 7, 1832 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Personal and Biographical
    - Five Year Diary of Mattie Haun, Jan. 1, 1939 – Dec. 31, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Diary of Mattie Haun, Jan. 1, 1944 – Dec. 31, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Diary of Mattie Haun, Jan. 1, 1935, Nov. 15, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Family records, accounts, diaries (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Family records, accounts, diaries (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Family records, accounts, diaries (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Family records, accounts, diaries, January 1932 – September 1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Family records, accounts, diaries, March 8, 1932 – January 1941 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Personal and Biographical
    - Family records, accounts, and diaries (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Notebook - Memory book, poems memorized by Mattie Haun (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Legal papers - 2 warranty deeds (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Legal papers - stock certificate; loan contract Feb. 17, 1932; Abstract of the Title to the Lands of B.S. Shields Now Known as Hortense Place (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Teacher’s certificates: 8 awarded to Andrew Haun, 1897 - 1917 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Diplomas received by A.J. Haun: National Co-operative Realty Co., Jan. 4, 1907; Summer School of the South, University of Tennessee, Knoxville, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Organizational Membership Cards - A.J. Haun - Dept. of Elementary School Principals; Free and Accepted Masons of TN; Knights Templar of TN; Royal Arch Masons of TN; TN Education Association (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Pamphlets - Bible, Religious, Devotional - “Auxiliary Devotional”, June 1941; “The Bible Teaches Temperance”; “Elders that Rule Well”; “Inquiring of God” (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Prayers and notes for religious services by Andrew Haun (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Inventory of all the goods and chattels of the estate of Andrew Jacob Haun, deceased (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Items: “Follow the Gleam”; “What Prohibition Has Done for Us”; “Colgate and Company- New York Perfumers” Booklet, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - “Our Wedding Bells” - Wedding notebook of Andrew J. Haun and Mattie Francis Oliver Haun, July 7, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Newspaper clippings – Williamson County News, Franklin, TN, Nov. 14, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Jewelry – one small box of jewelry belonging to Mattie Haun (Box 2, Folder 20)